A Guide to the Records of the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton, xxxx-xxxx
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton, xxxx-xxxx
The Library of Virginia
51684
xx cubic feet (xx boxes)
Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Privacy-protected information has been flagged and/or sealed, but not removed from the collection. Restricted information may include, but is not limited to: attorney-client privileged documents, medical information, and social security numbers.
Acquisition Information
Accession 51684 was transferred by the Virginia School for the Dead and Blind at Staunton, 29 October 2015.
Historical Information
The Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton was established by an Act of the General Assembly in 1906. The school officially opened September 8, 1909 as the Virginia School for Colored Deaf and Blind Children. After several name changes, the school was renamed the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind in 1980. In 1977 the General Assembly mandated that the school also serve sensory-impaired children with multiple disabilities, and the school named changed again in 2000 to the Virginia School for the Deaf, Blind and Multi-Disabled to include this recognition. The school operated under the Virginia Dept. of Education and the Virginia Board of Education The campus was situated on approximately 72 acres in the city of Hampton.
William Charles Ritter was instrumental in the establishment of the Virginia School for Colored Deaf and Blind Children. Ritter was born in 1872 in Clarke County, Virginia, and attended the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind located in Staunton, Virginia, after losing his hearing after contracting scarlet fever. He had deep interest in the education of deaf and blind African American children and in 1898, with the assistance of Del. Harry Rutherfor Houston, efforts began to create a school for these children. In 1906 an act appropriating five thousand dollars to begin work on the school passed in the General Assembly and in 1908, Governor Swanson appointed the first Board of Visitors. Mr. Ritter was selected as the first superintendent and land in Newport News was purchased for the site of the new school.
Scope and Content
XX
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, xxxx-xxxx
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, xxxx-xxxx., Extent: xx cu. ft. (xx boxes) (Box 1-xx)
  Correspondence and subject files, xxxx-xxxx, are housed in xx boxes and are arranged alphabetically. Includes mostly administrative correspondence and subject files, but also contains correspondence of the Superintentdent of VSDBH. Corresponendence was intermingled when transferred. Records contain correspondence, manuals, memoranda, policies, procedures.
  - Abuse policy, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accreditation, 1989-2003. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative manual, 1990 June. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administrative memoranda, 1983. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administrative memoranda, 1984 Jan-June. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administrative memoranda, 1984 July-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative memoranda, 1985 Jan-June. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Administrative memoranda, 1985 July-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Administrative memoranda, 1986. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Administrative memoranda, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Admissions procedures, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Aerial view, undated. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Plan, 1988. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual Special Education Plan, 1987-1988. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Spring Concert (program), 2000 May 25. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Appreciation certificates for use of building, 2000, undated. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Architectural drawings, 2000. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Assistant teacher meetings, 2001. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Briarfield Road property, 1961-1977. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Briarfield Road property, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Briarfield Road property, 1982-1983. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Briarfield Road property - Appraisals, 1969, 1979. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Budget - Program Exhibit, 1984-1990. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - By-laws, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cabinet site visit, 2000 Sept 13. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Campus Communications Systems survey, 1990. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Capital Programmatic Initiatives for VSDBH (1990-1992), 1989. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Capital Project request, 1990-1992. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Chronology - Window to the Past (1906-1984) (copy 1), undated. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chronology - Window to the Past (1906-1984) (copy 2), undated. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Classroom Study, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Commencement program, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Commencement program, 1969. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Commencement program, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Commencement program, 1994. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Commencement program, 1996. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Commencement program, 1997. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Commencement program, 1999. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Commencement program, 1999. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Commencement program, 2002. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Commencement program, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Commencement guestbook, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Commencement program, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 14a)
  - Commencement program, 2008. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Computer Camp, 1990. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Concerned Parents, Staff and Friends of the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton, 1989-1990. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Consolidation Project - Region II Special Education Interview Summary, 2007. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Convocation Ceremony program, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Core standards, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 1978-1981. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 1984. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 1985. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 1986. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 1987. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 1988. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 1990-2001. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 2002. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 2003. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 2004. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 2004-2005. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Administrative), 2004-2006. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Alignment (SOL), 2005. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Deaf USA article information, 2000. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Demographic Characteristics of the Hearing and Vision Impaired Student Population in Virginia Schools (Tayloe Murphy Study), 1988. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Departmental meeting, 1999 Aug 30. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Directory - Old Campus buildings, undated. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Education bills passed / Joint Resolutions agreed to by the 1990 General Assembly, 1990. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Education Staff Handbook, 2002-2003. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of, 1981-1982. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Affirmative Action Plan for Equal Opportunity Employment, 1989-1991. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Memoranda, 1989. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Regulatory), 1982 Oct-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Administrative), 1983-1984. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Regulatory), 1984 Aug-Nov. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Administrative), 1985 Jan-Mar. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Administrative), 1985 Apr. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Administrative), 1985 May-June. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Regulatory), 1985. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Administrative), 1985 July-Sept. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Administrative), 1986. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: Superintendent of Public Instruction memoranda (Regulatory), 1991 Jan, Apr-June. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: State Board of Education agendas, 1986. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: State Board of Education agendas, 1987. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: State Board of Education agendas, 1988. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: State Board of Education agendas, 1989. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: State Board of Education agendas, 1990. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: State Board of Education agendas, 1991. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Education, Virginia Dept. of: State Board of Education - Transition, 1980-1991. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Educational Coordinator, 1979. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Educational Interpreters in Virginia Public Schools: Factors Affecting Supply, Demand and Training (VDOE), 1993. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - End of Year Special Education Reports, 1985. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - End of Year Special Education Reports, 1986. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - End of Year Special Education Reports, 1987. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - End of Year Special Education Reports, 1988. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Division of (DGS), 1981. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Enrollment trends, 2005. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Extendent School Year Program, 1991. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Faculty qualifications, undated. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Family Day program, 2006 May 4-5. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Field Day, 2000 Sept 19. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Founder's Day, 1996. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Founder's Day Committee, 2005. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Future of VSDB, 1989. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Future Mission of VSDB-H, 1990. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Graduates, 1994-1999. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Graduates survey, 1994. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hampton Mayor's Committee for People with Disabilities, 2002-2006. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hearing and basics, undated. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Helton, Dr. William (Dir. of Special Education, VDOE) - Monthly meetings, 1989 Jan-Mar. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Helton, Dr. William (Dir. of Special Education, VDOE) - Monthly meetings, 1989 Apr-June. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Helton, Dr. William (Dir. of Special Education, VDOE) - Monthly meetings, 1989 July-Sept. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Helton, Dr. William (Dir. of Special Education, VDOE) - Monthly meetings, 1989 Oct-Dec. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Helton, Dr. William (Dir. of Special Education, VDOE) - Monthly meetings, 1990 Jan-Mar. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Helton, Dr. William (Dir. of Special Education, VDOE) - Monthly meetings, 1990 Apr-June. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Helton, Dr. William (Dir. of Special Education, VDOE) - Monthly meetings, 1990 July-Sept. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Historic documents (binder), 1985-1995, undated. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Historic documents (binder), 1996-1997. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Historical Highway marker, 2006. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Historical Museum at VSDBH brocure, 2007. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - In-depth Study Committee, 1983. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Individualized Education Program, 2000-2001. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Individualized Education Program, 2003. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Individualized Education Program, A Guide to the, 2000. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Information technology, 2002. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Instruction, Dept. of, 2004-2006. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Instruction - VI Space, 2004. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Interpreter Training Program, 1987. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Interpreter Training Program, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Interpreter Training Program, 1989. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Interpreter Workshop - Sign Language and Cued Speech, 1990. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Introduction of Individualized Education Program, 2002. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - James S. Johnson Fund, 1995-1996. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Legislation - H.B. 350, 2006. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Lesson plans, 2005 Sept. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Lesson plans (Elementary), 2005 Sept. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Lesson plans, 2005 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Lesson plans (Vocational Occupational Exporation), 2005 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Lesson plans (Elementary), 2005 Dec. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Lesson plans, 2005-2006. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Lesson plans (Emergency), 2005-2006. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Lesson plans (Elementary), 2006 Jan. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Marchant, Joann, 1989. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Mission, undated. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Mission, 1985-1987. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Mission and Future Programming, 1987-1991. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Mission and Future Programming - Reports, 1989-1990. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Mission and Future Programming - Reports, 1991. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Monthly Principal reports, 1990 Mar-May. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Multiculturalism (presentation), 2006 Nov. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Multi-Disabled Awareness Week (program), 2004 May 3-7. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - National Accreditation Council, 1977. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - National Accredication Council, 1978. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - National Accreditation Council, 1979. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - National Accreditation Council, 1982. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - National Accreditation Council, 1983. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - National Accreditation Council, 1985. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - New Horizons Regional Education Center, 2001. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - News articles, 1961-1978. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - News articles, 1979-1981. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - News articles, 1988-1997. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - News articles, 1999-2005. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - News articles, 2003. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - News articles, 2001-2005. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - News articles, 2004-2006. (Box 13a, Folder 1)
  - News articles, 2006. (Box 13a, Folder 2)
  - News articles, 2007-2009. (Box 13a, Folder 3)
  - News article - The Legal Necessity for Residential Schools Serving Deaf, Blind and Multi-Handicapped Sensory Impaired Children, undated. (Box 13a, Folder 4)
  - Norfolk State University, 1990. (Box 13a, Folder 5)
  - Organizational chart, 1982. (Box 13a, Folder 6)
  - Organization and Methods Study Report (VSDBH, copy 1), 1979 June. (Box 13a, Folder 7)
  - Organization and Methods Study Report (VSDBH, copy 2), 1979 June. (Box 13a, Folder 8)
  - Other states, 1996, undated. (Box 13a, Folder 9)
  - Pathway to Success (brochure), undated. (Box 13a, Folder 10)
  - Plans for the Future Direction of the Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind, 1990 Mar 29. (Box 13a, Folder 11)
  - Policies, 1978-1980. (Box 13a, Folder 12)
  - Policies, 1981-1982. (Box 13a, Folder 13)
  - Policies, 1983-1985. (Box 13a, Folder 14)
  - Policies, 1986-1987. (Box 13a, Folder 15)
  - Policies, 1988-1989. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Policy and Procedures regaring Student Abuse and Neglect, 2003. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Policy Manual (1 of 2), 1994. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Policy Manual (1 of 2), 1994. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Population charts, 1989. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Position paper - VSDBH, 1990 June 1. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Pre-Planning Study - Addition to Butler Hall, 1981. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Principal's Parley, 1987. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Problems of Education and the Handicapped ina Democratic Society, undated. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Program Guidelines for Students who are Visually Impaired, 1997-2000. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Proposal and Implementation Plan - Secondary School for the Deaf, 1980 c. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Proposal to Modify the Structure of the VSDBH to include a model residential program for handicapped gifted, 1988 Dec 16. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Public hearings, 1989-1990. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Public Relations: Communication Policy (Staunton), undated. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Public Relations: Correspondence, 1995-2000. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Public Relations: Correspondence regarding newsletter, 2006 May. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Public Relations: News releases, 1995-2000. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Public Relations: Publications, undated. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Public-Private Education and Infrastructure Act - Consolidation of the Hampton and Staunton Schools for the Deaf and Blind (DGS), 2005. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Records management, 2001. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Regulations, undated. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Reorganization, 1990-1991. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Utilization of the Facilities at the Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind, 1985 Dec 13. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Report on the Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind - A Review of the First Year, 1985 Sept 23. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Resolution G, 1984. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - School calendar, 2001-2002. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - School name, 1979-1989. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Service Delivery Options and Considerations for Students Who Have Sensory or Multiple Disabilities (VDOE), 1992. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Sign language, 1982. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sign language, 1983. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Sign language, 1983-1986. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Sign language, 1986-1987. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Sign language - Board of Visitors, 1980-1984. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Sign language - Class, 1988. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Sign language - History at VSDBH, undated. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Sign language - Manual Communication Policy and Evaluation Handbook, 1982. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Sign language - Manual Communication Policy, 1982-1986. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Sign language - Manual Communication Policy, 1987. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Sign language - Manual Communication Policy and Evaluation Handbook, 1987. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Sign language - Other states, 1987. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Sign language - Policy Model at VSDBH (Bellefleur and Harris), undated. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Sign language - Policy, 1980-1987. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Sign language - Policy Model, undated. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Six Year Corrective Action Plan, 1985. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Some statistical comparisons with the Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton and Staunton, 1989. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Special Projects Coordinator position, 1993. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Special Olympics, 1991. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Spring Fling, 2006 May 5. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Staff directory, undated. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Staff Handbook, 1994-1995. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Staff Handbook, 1995. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Staff meetings, 2001 Mar-2002 Jan. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Staff meetings, 2002 Aug. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Staff meetings, 2002 Sept. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Staff meetings, 2002 Oct. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Staff meetings, 2003. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Standards of Conduct (DHRM), 1993. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - State Operated Programs Education Directors, 1990-1991. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - State Operated Programs Education Directors, 1991-1994. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - State Plan for Implementing Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (VDOE), 1992. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Stategic Plan, 2004-2010. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Student Handbook, 1986. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Student Handbook, 1987. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Student Handbook, 1988. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Student records (presentation), 2002. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Study of Children's Residential Services (Planning and Budget), 1990. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Style Manual (VDOE), 1999. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Summer school, 1998. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Surveys related to Parents and School Divisions, 1986. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Thanksgiving Program, undated. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Transition - Status of Transition Recommendations, 1984-1985. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Transition for Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton, 1991. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton 90 Proud - An Historical Sketch, 1996. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton (brochure), undated. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind at Hampton (brochure; Braille), undated. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf, Blind and Multi-Disabled at Hampton - Meeting, 2000 Sept 12. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf, Blind and Multi-Disabled at Hampton - Meeting, 2001 Mar 14. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind: Comprehensive Report (VDOE), 1992. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Virginia's Handbook of Planning and Performance, 1998. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Vocational Education Awards luncheons (programs), 2001-2004. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, undated. (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Series II. Annual Reports, 1991-2002., Extent: .35 cu. ft. (1 box) (Box 19)
  Annual Reports, 1991-2002, are housed in 1 box and are arranged chronologically. Annual reports cover education services, student life, finances, operations, health services, strategic plannding and goals, and accomplishments.
  - Annual report, 1991-1992. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, 1992-1993. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Annual report, 1993-1994. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Annual report, 1994-1995. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Annual report, 1995-1996. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Annual report, 1996-1997. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Annual report, 1997-1998. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Annual report, 1998-1999. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Annual report, 1999-2000. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Annual report, 2000-2001. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Annual report (Braille), 2000-2001. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, 2001-2002. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Annual report (Braille), 2001-2002. (Box 31, Folder 1)
- Series III. Board of Visitors, 1970-1984., Extent: 1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes) (Box 20-22)
  Board of Vistitor records, 1970-1984, are housed in 3 boxes and are arranged by type of record. These records includes copies of minutes, agendas, correspondence, and reports.
  - Minutes, 1970-1972. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1980 Oct-1981 June. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1981 June-1982 Apr. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1982 June-Dec. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1983 Apr-Nov. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1984 Feb-Apr. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1978. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1980. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1981. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1982. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1983. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1984. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Virginia Schools (binder), 1981-1982. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - In-depth Study Committee (binder), 1981. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Scholarship Funds / Estates (binder), 1981-1982. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Least Restrictive Environment Blue Ribbon Task Force (binder), 1981-1982. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - General (binder), 1981-1982. (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Series IV. Committee and Council records, xxxx-xxxx., Extent: xx cu. ft. (x boxes) (Box 23-)
  Committee and Council records, xx-xx, are housed in x boxes and arraned alphabetically. Includes records for Ad Hoc Committee on the Utilization of Facilities at the Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind, Ad Hoc Program Task Force, Administrative Council,
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Utilization of Facilities at the Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind, 1985. (Box 23, Folder 1)